Wesley H. A. Silva, 30

61 Patterson Hill SW, Calgary, AB 604-721-8471 wesley.has@hotmail.com

Chef with a few years of experience in managing a restaurant and catering services for big events while focusing on quality service. Easy going and very fast learner. Focus and driven to archive goals.

Qualifications and Skills

- Main language Portuguese.
- Advanced English.
- Basic Spanish.
- Advanced computer skills.
- Intermediate hardware knowledge.
- Punctual, creative, interested, dedicated and responsible.

Education

11/31/2010

High School Graduation.

- 2008 Graduated in a 6-month hardware course.
- 2011 Study 3 years of Civil Engineering at Universidade do Oeste Paulista UNOESTE (Did not finish. Moved to Canada before being able to do so.)
- 2014 Graduated English at ILSC.

Other Experience

- Dishwasher and prep experience.
- A year and a half working as server back in Brazil.
- Great Typing skills.

Line Cook at Trattoria Italian Kitchen in Burnaby

Jul 2015 – Jun 2017

- Cook during service.
- General food preparation work
- Cleaning duties.

Chef De Partie at Trattoria Italian Kitchen in Burnaby

Jul 2017 – Jun 2018

- Assisted Banquet Chef with preparing food for events attended by up to 250 people.
- Observes service behaviors of associates and provides feedback to individuals; continuously strives to improve service performance.
- Develop daily features.
- Assist Sous Chef in training and developing staff.
- Hot line (average 250 covers/night) Fish/Accompaniments, Meat/Accompaniments, Inside Expediter.

Sous Chef at Trattoria Italian Kitchen in Burnaby

Jul 2018 – Sep 2018

- Managed and expedited food preparation line.
- Organize prep list for the prep cooks and assisted with completion at times.
- Order and receive food and supply weekly for restaurant operations. Check all temperatures of perishable items and used the FIFO system to rotate all items.
- Managed and supervised employees to make sure all tasks were completed and executed correctly.
- Manage food cost and labor.
- Back Of House inventory, controlled waste and variance of product to ensure proper food rotation.
- Maintained food quality, presentation, execution, health code standards.

Executive Chef at Trattoria Italian Kitchen in Burnaby

Oct 2018 – Feb 2019

- Supervised Banquet Chef with preparing food for events attended by up to 250 people.
- Supervised food cost, purchases, waste, BOH Scheduling and weekly inventory.
- Managed, hired, and developed BOH kitchen staff.
- Establish cost-effective portion sizes and cost estimates for menu additions or changes.
- Manage food cost and labor.
- Develop new menu items based on current techniques and market trends.
- Rectify arising problems or complaints.
- Keep time and payroll records.
- Ensures all equipment in the kitchen is properly maintained and in working order in accordance with local Health department and hotel standards.
- Maintain a positive and professional approach with coworkers and customers.

General Labor at Urban One Development

Jun 2019 – Feb 2020

• Cover any kind of job in a job site that the company assigned to.

General Labor at Mr. Rooter Vancouver

Feb 2020 – Feb 2021

- Tow excavator and operate it at needed job sites.
- Sewer line, storm line and water line repairs.

Unemployed/WCB

Apr 2021 – today

• Injured at work and had to go under surgery, currently going through physiotherapy.